Hey, everybody. Welcome to this A1
English listening practice video. You
can use this video to practice your
listening and comprehension as I speak.
And remember to sign up for our $1
listening practice seminars at
polyglossa.com
and download our free listening time
podcast so you can practice your
listening skills.
So today, I'm going to talk about the
English language. This is an important
topic for all of you because you're all
learning English. In this video, I'm
going to give you some interesting facts
about the English language. This should
be fun. Okay, so the first thing I want
to talk about is how many people speak
this language. Well, almost 400 million
people speak English as their first
language. These people are native
English speakers. Most of these speakers
are in the US, of course, but there are
many other English-speaking countries.
Obviously, countries like the UK,
Australia, Canada, and Ireland speak
English, but there are also a lot of
other countries where people speak
English. For example, English is the
major language of Belize, Guyana,
Jamaica, the Bahamas, and other
countries, too. There are a lot of
English-speaking countries. Also, many
people around the world speak English as
their second language. In every country,
there are people who are learning
English. As a teacher, I've taught
students from over 80 different
countries. Cool, huh? We don't know
exactly how many people speak English as
a second language, but there are a lot.
Okay, now let's talk about the history
of English. The first form of English
appeared in the 5th century AD.
Today, we call this early English Old
English. Old English was very different
from Modern English. I can't understand
Old English. In the 11th century, Old
English became Middle English. Middle
English is a little closer to Modern
English, but it's still very different.
Finally, Modern English began at the end
of the 14th century, but English
continues to change, so today's English
looks a little different from the
English of the past few centuries.
Another important thing to know about
English is that other languages have
influenced it a lot. So, which
languages? Well, for example, some
experts say that almost 30% of English
words come from Latin and almost 30% of
English words come directly from French.
That means that almost 60% of Modern
English words come from Latin or French.
That's a big influence. Also, around 6%
of English words come from Greek, and
there are many words from other
languages, too. But, what language
family does English belong to? English
is a Germanic language. That means
English is is
to languages such as German, Dutch, and
Swedish. However, English speakers can't
understand these other languages. If I
hear German or Dutch, I don't understand
anything. English is related to these
languages, but they're very different.
For example, Americans who only speak
English can usually understand much more
Spanish than German. That seems strange
because English and Spanish are not
related, but English and German are
related. The reason why English speakers
can understand many words from Spanish,
French, or Italian is because these
languages have many cognates. Cognates
are words that have the same origin. For
example, in English, we have the word
patience, and in Spanish, this word is
paciencia. These words look very similar
because they're cognates. So, if an
English speaker hears the Spanish word
paciencia, they can probably understand
the meaning. Okay, one last interesting
thing about English is that it has many,
many words. Some people say that English
is the language with the most words. I
think this is probably true because
English has taken many words from other
languages, like I said before. All
right, now I'm going to ask you some
questions about the video to see if you
understood. Write your answers in a
comment down below. Number one, when did
Old English appear? Number two, what
language family does English belong to?
And number three, what are cognates?
Okay, before we go, remember to sign up
for our $1 listening practice seminars
and download our free listening time
podcast to practice your listening
skills. And of course, subscribe to the
channel, click on the bell, and follow
us on Instagram. I'll see you next time.